《诉讼双雄》前情提要
Previously, on "Suits"...
我有架运输机运了一些艺术品
One of my transport flights was carrying some art.
由于机舱失压 其中一件损坏了
The hull depressurized, and one of the pieces got damaged.
它一定投过保 有什么问题？
It had to be insured, so what's the problem?
保险检查员居然敢说
The insurance inspector's got the balls to say
他们为此要起诉我赔偿
they'd be suing me for the damages.
我和一个国内顶级的生育专家约好了
I made an appointment with the top fertility specialist in the country.
你真的想我们需要看专家吗？
You really think we need a specialist?
我们越早得到帮助
The sooner we get some help,
就能越早抱上孩子
the sooner we can hold that baby in our arms.
两天前你说这个混帐
Two days ago, when you said this shady son of a bitch
故意毁掉那幅画
destroyed that painting intentionally--
你就是这样谈论你过去的客户的？
Is that how you talk about your former clients?
阿历克斯 这事对你来说输了
Alex, this thing is a loser for you.
控制好你的客户
Get your client under control.
别跟我说这个案子我输了
Don't talk to me about this case being a loser.
- 你很幸运我们今天在这里 - 废话
- You're lucky we're even in here. - Bullshit.
我们上法院 我会打赢你的
We go to court and I will clean your clock.
萨曼莎和阿历克斯即将开战
Samantha and Alex are about to go to war.
- 我叫她和解 - 她没有
I told her to settle. - Well, she didn't.
如果萨曼莎这样做 我来处理
And if Samantha did that, I'll deal with her.
怎么处理？自从她加入以来
How? Because you've let her do
你让她为所欲为
whatever she wants ever since she got here.
我猜让你在阿历克斯这件事上让步
I don't suppose it would do any good
不会有好结果
to ask you to let Alex go up there first.
我不会退让的 因为
I'm not backing down because
我认为我比阿历克斯·威廉姆斯出色
I think I'm better than Alex Williams,
我不否认我也这么想
and I'm not gonna say that I'm not.
你子宫颈有一些肌瘤
You have some cervical fibroids
不幸的是 你的妇科医生忽略了
that, unfortunately, your OB missed,
我准备切除它们
and I'd like to remove them.
如果我们继续什么也不做......
If we keep doing nothing...
这比让他们自己解决更糟糕
It's worse than letting them settle it themselves.
一个案子定胜负 赢家成为冠名合伙人
One case, head-to-head, winner gets name partner.
你俩都知道
As you both know,
哈维和我各自做出承诺
Harvey and I each made a promise
让你们成为冠名合伙人
to put your names on the door next.
显然不可能我俩都守诺
And obviously it's not possible for us both to keep that promise.
别告诉我俩会同时晋升
This better not be you telling us we're going up at the same time,
因为就我而言
because as far as I'm concerned,
就像说只晋升他一样瞎闹
that's as bullshit as telling me you're giving it to him.
这次你和我意见一致
And for once, you and I agree.
很好 因为我们有另一个想法
Good, because we have another idea.
跟我想的一样吗？
Are those what I think they are?
豁免两位的利益冲突
Two conflict of interest waivers
允许你们面对面一决雌雄
giving you the green light to take off the gloves and get in the ring.
你们如愿以偿可以斗一斗了
You wanted a fight. You got it.
获胜者接下来会成为冠名合伙人
The winner gets their name up next.
有问题吗
Any questions?
我有
I got one.
它会是“和威廉姆斯”吗？
Is it gonna be "and Williams,"
还是“赞恩-斯伯特克-利特-威廉姆斯”
or just "Zane Specter Litt Williams"?
我可以回答这个问题
I can answer that.
两个都不是
It's not gonna be either one.
我想我们只好走着瞧了
Then I guess we'll just have to find out.
奉陪到底
I guess we will.
好了 在你开始之前
Well, before you start taking any swings,
我想澄清一件事
I wanna make one thing clear:
这是一场公平竞赛
This is a fair fight.
不许使用内幕消息
No using inside information.
不许挖对方老底
No looking at the other person's shit.
清楚吗
Are we clear?
- 是的 - 清楚
- Yes. - Clear.
如果大家都没问题
And if no one else is gonna say it, I will.
准备开始吧
Let's get ready to rumble.
哈维 你来干什么
Harvey. What are you doing here?
我想说我知道这不是我们所预计的
I came to say I know this isn't how either of us thought this would go down.
我想确保你能好好对待这事
And I wanted to make sure you were good with it.
如果非要这样
If this is what it's gonna take,
那我不仅仅善长处理它
then I'm not just good with it.
我还很擅长这个
I'm also good with this.
让我猜猜
Let me guess.
你希望我为你处理这事
You want me to take care of this for you.
你又不是没干过
It's nothing you haven't done before.
不是说
What happened to
你不喜欢我指手划脚吗
you don't like it when I get involved?
我要你别管时
What I don't like is you getting involved
我不喜欢你指手划脚
when I asked you to stay out of it.
这次是我要你帮忙
This is me telling you to get your ass in it.
好吧 亚历克斯
All right, Alex.
你确定吗？
Are you sure?
一旦这样 覆水难收
Because once I do this, there's no taking it back.
是的 我肯定
Yes, I'm sure.
因为我向你保证
Because I guarantee you,
她同样会去找罗伯特
she's going to Robert to do the same damn thing.
所以问题是你帮不帮我
So the question is, are you here for me or not?
我帮你 亚历克斯 我就是来帮你的
I'm here for you, Alex. I'm right the hell here.
- 总算找到你了 - 不行
- Good, you're here. - No.
什么叫不行
What do you mean no?
你甚至都不知道我想要什么
You don't even know what I want.
废话 我当然知道
- Bullshit, I don't.
你来找我帮你对付阿历克斯·威廉姆斯
You're here for some kind of edge with Alex Williams,
我不会答应的
and I'm not gonna give it to you.
- 为什么 - 因为如果我帮你
Why not? - Because if I step in to help you,
就破坏了整个安排
it undermines the whole arrangement.
我要的是把审判推迟一周
All I'm asking is to delay the trial a week.
萨曼莎 我之所以是管理合伙人
Samantha, I'm managing partner here because
我知道什么时候该置身事外
I stayed out when it was time. Well, it's still time.
如果你想推迟这案子的审理
And if you wanna delay this thing,
你必须自己去做
you're gonna have to do it on your own.
- 胡说八道 - 随你怎么想
That is bullshit. - And you're entitled to your opinion.
除非还你有别的事
Now, unless you got some other business,
不然让我好好洗洗手
why don't you just let me wash my hands in peace?
* 看到钱  就愿意留下吃饭 *
* See the money, wanna stay for your meal *
* 给你太太再拿块馅饼 *
* Get another piece of pie for your wife *
* 所有人都想知道那感觉 *
* Everybody wanna know how it feel *
* 所有人都想见见那景象 *
* Everybody wanna see what it's like *
* 豆子馅饼我也愿吃  我不在乎 *
* I'll even eat a bean pie, I don't mind *
* 我和妹子忙着赚钱 *
* Me and Missy is so busy, busy making money *
* 好了
* All right
* 退开点  我要跳舞 *
* All step back, I'm 'bout to dance *
诉讼双雄
第八季 第十集
* 美钞爵士摇摇摇
* The greenback boogie
翻译 时间轴： 等不到人人字幕只好自己做的Ausley
十二年前
谢谢
Thank you.
刚下班还是刚开始
You ending the night or starting the day?
- 两者都是 - 我也一样
Both. - Same here.
银行家还是律师？
Banker or lawyer?
没兴趣跟你聊
What I am is not interested.
嗯 你可能不感兴趣
Well, you might not be interested,
但你得好好听着
but you're going to listen.
我们可以公事公办 萨曼莎
Now, we can be formal about this, Samantha,
或者你可以叫我汤姆
or you can just call me Tom.
好吧 汤姆 我在听
Okay, Tom. I'm listening.
我们知道你的律所里有人洗钱
We know there's money laundering going on in your firm,
但我们不知道牵涉有多深
but we don't know how high up the food chain it goes.
局里认为你会是一个合适的人
And the bureau thinks that you'd be the perfect person
帮我们搞清这个问题
to help us answer that question.
为什么是我
Why me?
我们知道你曾经为国服役
We know that you served your country once before.
这是再次报国的机会
This is a chance to serve it again.
好吧 你可以随意煽动爱国热情
Well, you can wave the flag all you want,
但我什么都不知道 我忠于
but I don't know anything, and I'm loyal to the people
现在在一起工作的人
I'm in the foxhole with right now.
好吧 如果你不想问你能为国家做什么
Well, if you're not gonna ask what you can do for your country,
那么...
then...
也许你应该问一下国家能对你做些什么
maybe you should ask what your country can do to you.
- 这些记录是密封的 - 曾经是
These records were sealed. - They were.
它们是否保持密封完全取决于你的选择
And whether they stay sealed is entirely your choice.
看看你能挖出什么
See what you can dig up,
不要对任何人说这事
and don't say a word about this to anyone.
通常不会进来坐下
You don't usually come in and sit right down.
这事一定很重要
This must be important.
我得说说这案子的事
I need to say something about this trial,
我需要你听我说
and I need you to hear me.
唐娜 如果这跟我们没有咨询你有关
Donna, if this is about us not consulting you,
这是冠名合伙人的决定
it was a name partner decision.
跟那无关 哈维
It's not about that, Harvey.
我要谈的是当这事结束时我们要做什么
I'm here to talk about what we're gonna do when it's over.
- 什么意思？ - 不管输赢
What do you mean? - We're all still gonna
我们还在这里 你得保持这里的和平
be here, and win or lose, it's gonna be on you to keep the peace.
我希望你同样问过赞恩
I hope you're asking the same of Zane.
- 没有 - 为什么
I'm not. - Why not?
因为这依然更像是你的律所
Because this is still more your firm than his,
每个人都知道
and everybody knows it.
所以如果亚历克斯获胜
So if Alex wins,
你需要有雅量
you need to be magnanimous about it.
哈维 如果萨曼莎获胜 你需要更有雅量
And Harvey, if Samantha wins, you need to be the bigger man
优雅地接受它
and accept it with grace.
你认为阿历克斯不会赢 是吗？
You don't think Alex can win, do you?
- 如果我说对呢 - 我想知道为什么
What if I said I don't? - I'd wanna know why.
因为这无关于谁是更好的律师
Because this isn't about who the better lawyer is.
这关于获胜
It's about winning.
除非他突然变了一个人
And unless he suddenly becomes a different person,
他不愿像她一样尽力去赢
he's not willing to go as far as she is to win.
也许他正在成为一个不同的人
Well then maybe he is becoming a different person.
- 什么意思？ - 他来找我帮忙
What do you mean? - I mean he came to me for help,
他没有求我 而是要我帮忙
and he wasn't asking. He was telling.
- 你答应了 - 我答应了
And you gave it to him? - I did.
哈维 如果阿历克斯再来找帮忙 别答应
Harvey, if Alex comes to you asking for help again, say no.
为什么
Why?
因为这不仅仅是为了以后保持和平
Because this isn't just about keeping the peace later.
如果我们不小心
If we're not careful,
还没结束就会让我们四分五裂了
this could rip us apart before it's even over.
这是什么
What's all this?
只是想确保你有我们所有的证据
Just wanted to make sure you had all of our discovery.
你带给我一大堆文件
You're bringing me a cartload of documents
晚上9点让我看？
to go through at 9:00 at night?
这只是冰山一角
And this is just the tip of the iceberg.
你可能要订外卖了
You might wanna order takeout.
有多少是纯粹浪费我时间的东西？
How much of this is purely to waste my time?
你自己看吧 但说到时间...
I'll leave that to you, but speaking of time...
难以置信
I don't believe it!
你把庭审改到了明天？
You moved the trial to tomorrow?
我不会拐弯抹角 萨曼莎
I don't run the four corners, Samantha.
我快刀斩乱麻
I fast-break.
好戏开始了
And right now, it's show time.
你以为我不知道你在做什么？
You think I don't know what you're doing?
你想加快这事 因为你知道
You're trying to speed this thing up because you know
你的客户有罪 就像你知道
your client is guilty, just like you know
如果我有时间 我会证明这一点
if I have time to dig in, I'll prove it.
我想加快速度 因为时间越长
I'm trying to speed this up because the longer
我客户的形象
this goes on, the longer my client's image
陷入麻烦就越久
gets dragged through the mud.
饶了我吧 亚历克斯
Spare me the song and dance, Alex.
法官可能被蒙在鼓里 但我没有
The judge might not have seen through it, but I do.
没错 他确实像我希望的一样
You're right. He did see it my way.
而你唯一能看到的就是
And the only thing you're gonna see is me wiping the floor
明天开始我无往不胜
with you starting tomorrow.
- 是我 - 路易斯
Yeah? - Louis.
嘿 我正在想你
Hey, I was just thinking about you.
怎么哪 你今天好吗
What's going on? How was your day?
我有一些好消息和坏消息
Well, I've got some good news and some bad news.
- 出什么事了 - 斯坦顿院子的妻子
What happened? - dean Stanton's wife
被诊断出患有乳腺癌
was diagnosed with breast cancer,
他退下来去陪她
and he's stepping down to spend some time with her.
希拉 我很抱歉
Sheila, I am so sorry.
好消息是他推荐我
The good news is he recommended me
作为临时院长
to be interim dean.
哦 天啊 太好了 我现在回家
Oh, my God, that's amazing. I'm gonna come home right now
我们要出去庆祝一下
and we're gonna go out and celebrate.
路易斯 你不必这样做
Louis, you don't have to do that.
嗯 我知道 但我想要
Well, I know I don't have to. I want to.
不 我的意思是 你不必这样做
No, I mean, you don't have to do that.
因为我已经到这里了
Because I'm already here.
我很为你感到骄傲
I am so proud of you.
路易斯 还没有生效呢
Louis, it hasn't happened yet.
会的
It will.
我知道会的
I know it will.
对不起 贾维斯先生
Excuse me, Mr. Jarvis.
能打扰你几分钟吗？
Do you have a minute?
当然可以
Of course I do.
但首先我需要知道你的名字
But first I'll need a name.
我叫萨曼莎·惠勒
Samantha Wheeler.
好吧 萨曼莎·惠勒
Well, Samantha Wheeler,
我能为你做点什么？
what can I do for you?
我入职时被告知有事可以找高级管理层
When I was hired I was told I could come to senior management with anything.
你可以
And you can.
我们很自豪
We pride ourselves on our reputation
能照顾我们的同事
for looking after our associates.
这就是为什么我希望您能帮我
Which is why I'm hoping you can help me.
今天早上联邦调查局找我
I was approached by the FBI this morning.
他们认为这里正在发生一些事
They think something's going on here.
哦
Oh.
你怎么说？
And, well, what did you say?
我说我忠于我的公司
I said I'm loyal to my firm.
好吧 那说明有什么东西
Well, that would presume there's something
值得忠诚
to be loyal about.
那个找我的人相信
The guy that came at me believes
我们在洗钱
we're laundering money.
你在忙什么案子
What are you working on right now?
对孟山都的诉讼
The suit against Monsanto.
明天第一件事 我找别人去做
First thing tomorrow, I'm farming it out to someone else,
如果联邦调查局是对的
because if the FBI's right,
我需要有人来查查我们的账
then I need someone to dig into our books.
如果我去找会计 那么无论谁干的这事
If I go to accounting, then whoever's doing this
一定知道把事深深藏起来
is gonna know there's something rotten in Denmark.
- 我去做 - 很好
- I'm on it. - Good.
哦 萨曼莎 如果你发现什么
Oh, and Samantha, if you find anything,
无论多小 告诉我
I mean, no matter how small, please, let me know.
女士们 先生们 庭审中你们会听到
Ladies and gentlemen, you're going to hear a lot
数字 但唯一重要的数字
of numbers in this trial, but the only number
是七
that matters is seven.
这是保持货舱不会失压的保障措施
That's how many safeguards there are to keep a cargo hold from depressurizing.
它根本不可能发生
It simply can't happen.
除非有人想要它发生
Unless someone wants it to happen.
20年前 我把车停在7-Eleven外面
20 years ago, I parked my car outside a 7-Eleven.
当我出来时 它彻底毁了
When I came out, it was totaled,
花了两年时间才收到我负担不起的
and it took me two years to collect $1,800
1,800美元损失
I couldn't afford to lose.
加文·安德鲁斯从中受益上百万美元
Gavin Andrews stood to gain millions of dollars
通过他被指控运输中毁掉那幅画
from destroying the very painting he was charged with transporting.
想象一下它不是卡罗拉
Now, imagine it wasn't a Corolla.
而是一幅价值1亿美元的画作
It was a $100 million painting.
想想他们竭尽全力不想付钱
Think how hard they'll fight not to pay.
因为这就是保险公司所做的事
Because it's what insurance companies do.
他们责怪别人
They blame someone else.
他们称之为不可抗力
They call it an act of God.
或者只是说 “有本事你来拿吧”
Or they just say, "Screw you. Come and get it."
事实上这是一种犯罪
The truth is, this is a crime,
他应该去坐牢
and he should go to prison for it.
不幸的是我们不能把他绳之以法
Unfortunately we can't put him away for this,
但我们能做的就是让他为此付出代价
but what we can do is make him pay for it.
因为他们会尽竭全力来保住他们的钱
Because they'll do whatever it takes to keep their money.
我们不会让他们得逞的
And we're not gonna let them get away with it.
惠勒小姐 你的第一个证人
Miss Wheeler, your first witness.
法官大人 我传唤加文·安德鲁斯
Your Honor, I call Gavin Andrews to the stand.
我猜你不喜欢前戏啊
I guess you aren't big on foreplay.
哦 我喜欢前戏 亚历克斯
Oh, I like foreplay just fine, Alex.
但有一件事你是对的
But you're right about one thing.
你很快就知道了
You're about to get ----ed.
安德鲁斯先生 当飞机减压时
Mr. Andrews, when a plane depressurizes,
应该让运输安全委员会进行调查
the NTSB is supposed to investigate.
但在他们检查前你就清空了货舱
But before they could, you cleared out the cargo hold.
为什么要这么做？
Why would you do that?
因为你不想让数百万美元的艺术品
Because you don't leave million-dollar works of art
暴晒在阳光下
to bake in the sun.
我的决定挽救了其中的大部分
And thanks to my call, we were able to save most of them.
大部分
Most of them.
但不包括《维梅尔》
But not the Vermeer.
如果世界上少了一幅《维梅尔》
And if there's one less Vermeer in the world,
你的会更值钱
then yours in more valuable.
抱歉让你失望了
Sorry to disappoint you,
但我不想那幅画毁了 我想买下它
but I didn't want that painting destroyed. I wanted to buy it.
我们来谈谈你的其他艺术品吧
Then let's talk about your other art.
五年前
Five years ago,
你以八百万美元买了一幅雷诺阿的画
you bought a Renoir for $8 million
最近卖了它 对吗？
and recently sold it. Is that correct?
- 是的 - 卖多少钱？
It is. - How much did you sell it for?
相当多
Considerably more.
卖了5500万美元对不对
Isn't it true you sold it for $55 million
卖给了后来正巧赢了你生意的航空公司
to an airline manufacturer who then happened to win your business?
法官大人 这违反了我们的豁免条款
Your Honor, that's a violation of the terms of our waiver.
她正在使用机密信息
She's using privileged information.
原来可能是机密 但安德鲁斯先生的妻子
It would be privileged, except Mr. Andrews' wife
在他们的离婚文件中记录了所有细节
detailed all of this in their divorce filing.
- 什么？ - 他在婚前协议中
What? - He hid assets
隐瞒了资产
from their prenuptial agreement.
他收受贿赂并将其藏在艺术品交易中
He took bribes and hid them as art transactions--
法官大人 传闻而已
Hearsay, Your Honor.
一个满怀仇恨的前妻的无端指控
Allegations from a bitter ex-wife.
一个比任何人都更了解这个男人的女人
A woman who knows this man better than anyone.
反对无效 威廉姆斯先生
Overruled, Mr. Williams.
离婚文件是公开的
Divorce filings are publicly available.
安德鲁斯先生 你从供应商那里收取回扣
Mr. Andrews, you take kickbacks from your suppliers.
欺骗自己的妻子
You cheated your own wife.
你真的希望陪审团相信《维梅尔》这事
Do you really expect a jury to believe what happened to the Vermeer
- 是一次意外？ - 确实是意外
was an accident? - It was an accident.
好吧 事实胜于雄辩
Well, actions speak louder than words.
你的行为不仅仅是雄辩
And your actions aren't just speaking.
它们尖叫着你是有罪的
They are screaming that you're guilty
所有人都可以听到它
and all of these people can hear it.
见鬼 你打破了我们达成的协议
God damn it, we had an agreement, and you broke it.
我没有
I didn't break anything.
别胡说八道 离婚文件根本没有公开记录
Don't give me that shit. There's no public record of that divorce filing,
他老婆也没可能知道那5500万美元
and there's no way his wife knew about that $55 million.
那你自己去查档案
Then go check the filing yourself.
我想你会发现它最近被修改过了
I think you'll find that it's been recently amended
而且放入了公开记录
and placed in the public record,
这意味着我没有违反任何协议
which means I didn't violate anything.
好吧 萨曼莎你想要公开记录
All right, Samantha. You want public record.
我会给你公开记录
I'll give you public record.
霍福德女士 不是检查整个监管环节
Ms. Horford, instead of looking at the whole chain of custody,
你只专注于右舷航空公司
you only focused on Starboard Airlines.
为什么？
Why is that?
我们检查了整个监管环节 威廉姆斯先生
We looked at the whole chain of custody, Mr. Williams.
用了多长时间？10分钟？
For how long? Ten minutes?
一小时？
An hour?
还是只花了时间来算计你可以起诉的人
Or just long enough to figure that of all the people you could sue,
加文·安德鲁斯是最有钱的人
Gavin Andrews had the deepest pockets?
这是侮辱人 我们不会这样做的
That's insulting. We don't do business that way.
我想你就是这样做的 这就是你丢了
I think you do, which is why you lost
右舷航空公司这个客户的原因
Starboard Airlines as a client
加文·安德鲁斯把生意给别人了
when Gavin Andrews took his business elsewhere. -
与此完全无关
That has nothing to do with this. -
跟你丢了那年的奖金有关
It has to do with you missing out on your bonus that year.
如果你暗示我出于个人原因利用公司
If you're implying that I would use my company for personal reasons
这不是你指责我的客户做的吗？
Isn't that what you're accusing my client of doing?
当高盛的一位分析师问你
And when an analyst at Goldman asked you
为什么丢了右舷航空公司的生意
why you lost Starboard Airlines,
你说
you said,
“加文·安德鲁斯做生意的方式会有报应的”
"The way Gavin Andrews does business will come back to haunt him,"
意味着你会回来报应他
meaning you would come back to haunt him.
我不是那个意思
That's not what I meant.
这听起来像是
It sure sounds like what it meant.
我的意思是我们最大的竞争对手给了他回扣
What I meant was that our biggest rival gave him a kickback to drop
你有证据吗？
You have proof of that?
不 你没有
No, you don't,
就像你没有证据证明
just like you don't have proof
我客户损坏了那幅画一样
that my client damaged that painting.
你有的只是一堆诽谤和怨恨
All you have is a bunch of smear tactics and a grudge.
- 反对 自己作证 - 我收回
- Objection, testifying-- - Then I'll wrap it up.
因为你是对的 事实胜于雄辩
Because you were right: actions do speak louder than words.
这一切都是一个典型的报复案例
And all this is is a good old fashioned case of payback.
我收到留言就马上回来了
I came home as soon as I got the voicemail.
我得到这份工作了
I got the job.
希拉 太棒了 我为你感到非常骄傲
Sheila, that is fantastic. I am so proud of you.
不仅如此 他们说如果我做得好
And not only that, they said if I do well,
我可以终身做下去
I can have it permanently.
- 终身的？ - 是的
Permanently? - Yes.
他们在讨论
They were discussing it,
搜寻委员会负责人说......
and the head of the search committee said...
路易斯 怎么哪？
Louis, what's wrong?
没什么 只是我们同意有了宝宝后
Nothing, it's just we agreed after the baby,
我会在秋天干重活
I'd do the heavy lifting in the fall,
你会在招生季结束后接手
and you would take over after recruiting season ended.
希拉 但法学院院长
The dean of a law school, Sheila,
是一个全年的工作
that's a year-round job.
你无法两者兼顾
There's no way you'll be able to do both.
好吧 我们可以做一些调整
Well, we can--we can make an adjustment.
- 什么样的调整？ - 我不知道
What kind of adjustment? - Well, I don't know.
大多数全职夫妻不都会找一个保姆吗？
Don't most couples with full-time jobs get a nanny?
我不想让一个陌生人带我的孩子
I don't want a stranger raising my child.
所以你要我拒绝一个
So you want me to turn down an opportunity
可能永远不会再有的机会？
that may never come again?
临时可以
Not the interim part,
但永久不行
but the permanent part, yes.
路易斯 如果这样 我们有了一个女儿
Louis, if I did that and we have a daughter,
我怎么对她说？
how would I ever look her in the eye?
你看着她的眼睛告诉她
You look at her in the eye and you tell her,
“我选择了你”
"I chose you."
如果不这样
If you don't,
你将永远无法照看她了
you'll never be able to look her in the eye at all
因为你要工作
because you'll be working.
好吧 这不公平 路易斯
Okay, that's not fair, Louis.
如果我们能解决犹太人的事
And if we worked out the Jewish thing,
我们也可以解决这个
we can work this out.
那事我们还没解决
Well, we haven't figured that out yet.
那是我们没有讨论好的事
And that was something we hadn't discussed.
这是我们同意的
This is something we agreed on.
就像我们同意
Like when we agreed
你会放弃泥浴 结果你没有
you'd give up mudding, and then you didn't.
别怪回我身上
Don't throw that back on me.
我最终还是放弃了它
I lived up to it in the end.
好吧 路易斯 这事比泥浴重要
Okay, well this is a little bit bigger than mudding,
路易斯 这是我的生活
Louis. This is my life.
我想要这份工作
And I want this job
我想要一个孩子
and I want a baby
我不明白为什么我不能两者兼得
and I don't see why I can't have both.
好吧 我不知道该怎么说
Well, I don't know what to say to all that.
“我支持你的选择”？
How about, "I support your choices?"
我将在三天内接受手术
Because I'm gonna have surgery in three days
来帮助我们拥有这个孩子
to help us have this baby.
知道我们想法一致
And I'd feel a lot better about it
会让我自己感觉好很多
knowing we were both on the same team.
罗伯特
Robert.
萨曼莎
Samantha.
你在这里做什么？
What are you doing down here?
一个客户的账单出错了
There was an error with a client's billing.
我想在被发现之前改正它
I'm trying to fix it before it gets noticed.
哪个客户？也许我可以帮忙
Which client? Maybe I can help.
谢谢 我自己来吧
I appreciate that. I just took care of it.
晚安
Have a nice night.
萨曼莎
Samantha.
不是会计师的人只有两个原因
There's only two reasons someone who's not an accountant
星期五晚上会在这里
would be here on a Friday night.
要么找不到约会对象 要么......
Either they can't get a date, or...
他们想趁无人时来这里
they want to be here when no one's around.
您在说什么
What are you saying?
你不是来改东西的
You're not here to fix something.
你来这里找东西
You're here to find something.
不是的
That's not what I'm do
没关系
It's okay.
我来也是为了同样的事
I'm here for the same thing.
公司里钱的事上有些猫腻
There's something shady going on here with the money.
我无法证明这点
I just can't prove it.
就算我相信您
Let's say I trust you.
目前为止您发现了什么？
What have you found so far?
两件事
There's two issues.
奖金支出和固定费用
Bonus payments and retainer fees.
没错
Exactly.
这样吧
So I tell you what.
你查固定费用 我查奖金
You take the retainers. I'll take the bonuses.
一周后 我们碰碰看查到什么
A week from now, we meet up and see what's what.
听起来不错
Sounds like a plan.
罗伯特 您为什么要这样做？
Robert, why are you doing this?
因为我不介意为罪犯辩护
Because I don't mind defending criminals,
但我学法律不是为了为他们工作
but I don't put myself through law school to work for them.
好吧 你需要帮助
All right, you wanted help.
这就是帮助
Well, here it is.
我想要的是昨天帮我
What I wanted was help yesterday.
您说不行 现在已经太晚了
You said no, and now it's too late.
庭审已经开始了
The trial's already started.
好吧 我错了
Well, I was wrong.
所以你可以耿耿于怀
So you can hold a grudge,
也可以想想其他要帮的事
or you can think of something else.
好吧
All right.
有一件事
There is one thing.
亚力克斯在庭上把尼娜驳得哑口无言后
After Alex tore Nina to pieces on the stand,
我告诉她我们需要巩固
I told her we needed to shore up
对包装公司的调查
the investigation into the packing company.
她脸上的神色
She got a look on her face.
什么样的神色
What kind of look?
好像说我什么也不能巩固的样子
The kind of look that said I'm not gonna be able to shore up anything.
所以我说 “算我没问”
So I said, "Forget I asked."
让我猜猜 她已经把文件送过来了
Let me guess. She already sent the files over.
回来后我很确定已经送来了
I'm pretty sure they got here after I got back.
但我不知道 因为我没看
But I don't know since I didn't look.
这意味着你需要我让那个盒子消失
Which means you need me to make that box disappear.
是的
Yes, I do.
萨曼莎......
Samantha...
让我问你一个问题
let me ask you one question:
你确定加文·安德鲁斯有罪吗？
are you sure Gavin Andrews is guilty?
罗伯特 我代理这个人多年了
Robert, I represented the man for years.
他总是有罪的
He is always guilty.
然后逍遥法外
Then consider it gone.
10点 很准时
10:00, right on schedule.
如果不准时 我算什么人
I'm nothing if not prompt.
你找到了什么
So, what'd you come up with?
什么也没有
Not a thing.
所有固定费用都没问题
The retainers all checked out.
见鬼
Shit.
见什么鬼
Why shit?
我查了奖金也没问题
Well, I dug into the bonuses and struck out, too.
也许本来就没什么问题
Maybe there's nothing to find.
我没说一无所有 罗伯特
I didn't say I didn't find anything, Robert.
我说固定费用没问题
I said the retainers all checked out.
查完我的后
After I went down my path,
我又查了你的 你不知道吗？
I went down yours, and wouldn't you know?
直接查到你身上
It led right back to you.
罗伯特 请告诉我
So tell me, Robert.
为什么有一笔10万美元的
Why am I holding a $100,000
账外电汇有你的名字在上面
off-the-books wire transfer with your name on it?
六个月前 我发现三个合伙人
Six months ago I found out all three named partners
都在洗钱
were laundering money.
他们提议让我加入 我拒绝了
They offered to cut me in. I said no.
他把钱汇在我账上 让我看起来是同谋
He put that money in there to make me look complicit.
胡说八道
Bullshit.
这不是胡说八道
It's not bullshit.
无论我怎么说 他们都不收回这笔钱
They wouldn't take the money back no matter what I said.
所以我只好退而求其次 把它捐给了慈善机构
So I did the next best thing and gave it to charity.
如果不相信 我给你看支票
If you don't believe me, I'll show you the check.
您可以不要支票 但您不能上报吗？
So you can cut a check but you can't blow the whistle?
多么高贵啊
How noble.
事情比这更复杂
It's more complicated than that.
对我来说似乎很简单
Seems pretty simple to me.
您目击了犯罪 您得报告当局
You witness a crime, you tell the authorities.
这就是我现在要做的
Which is what I'm gonna do right now.
为什么不等你有女儿后再告诉我？
Why don't you try telling me that after you have a daughter?
她名叫瑞秋
Her name is Rachel.
她想成为一名律师
She wants to be a lawyer.
但是当她向律师协会申请时
But how is that gonna go when she applies to the bar
他们会说
and they say,
“你父亲不是罪犯吗？”
"Isn't your father a criminal?"
您给他们看支票
You show them the check
让他们相信您不是罪犯
and make them believe you're not a criminal.
这样的话我的名誉将永远受到伤害
If this comes out, my name is tainted forever.
他们永远不会相信我
They'll never believe me.
如果只是我 我会试一试
And if it was just me, I'd take that chance.
对不起 罗伯特 这...
I'm sorry, Robert. It's...
这不是我能决定的
It's not my call.
求你了
Please.
你来找我是因为你想听听我的说法
Now, you came in here because you wanted to hear my side of the story.
我的说法...
My story...
我是一个有女儿的父亲
is I'm a father with a daughter.
我需要你的帮助
And I need your help.
萨曼莎
Samantha.
我还在想你什么时候大驾光临呢
I was wondering when this visit was coming.
为了什么？
What visit is that?
来威胁我
you threaten me.
我不是来威胁你的
I'm not here to threaten you.
我来给你提供一条出路
I'm here to offer you a way out
免得你受到公开羞辱
before publicly humiliating you
因为你仍然是我公司的客户
because you're still a client of my firm.
滚出我的地盘
Get off my property.
如果那样 陪审团会听到
And I do that, the jury's gonna hear
来自菲利普·琼斯的证词
from Phillip Jones.
你以为你可以把他藏起来
You thought you could hide him from me.
我不认识这个人
I don't know anyone by that name.
真好笑 因为有监控录像显示
Funny, because he has security footage showing you
两周前你和他见过面
meeting with him two weeks before
你摧毁了那幅画
you destroyed that painting.
他永远不会作证的
He'll never testify.
他已经作了
He already has.
他发誓说你特意问过他
I have him under oath saying you specifically asked him
你的《维梅尔》会涨多少
how much your Vermeer would go up
如果另一幅被毁了的话
if another one got destroyed.
我吃定你了 加文 我不会放手的
I've got you, Gavin, and I am not letting go.
这是非法的 不可接受的
This is illegal and inadmissible.
你黑了我
You hacked my shit.
我对你做的
What I did was do to you
是我曾经为你做的
what I used to do for you.
你可以威胁我或者把我从你的地盘上赶走
And you can threaten me or throw me off your property
但是一旦我们上庭
but once we're in that courtroom,
我绝不退让
I am not going anywhere.
给我一天时间
Give me a day.
你说什么？
Excuse me?
我会付我们欠的钱
I'll pay what we owe.
我只是需要一天得到董事会的批准
I just--I need a day to get the board's approval.
不 我不相信你
No, I don't trust you.
你不需要相信我 你吃定我了
You don't need to trust me. You got me.
就像你刚才说的那样
Like you just said.
我仍然是公司的客户
I'm still a client of the firm.
多少有点面子
That's gotta count for something.
没有
It doesn't.
萨曼莎 拜托了
Samantha, please.
我知道你曾经跟我谈过你的家人
I know you once told me about your family.
我也有一个家庭
Well, I have a family and...
如果出现这种情况
If this comes out,
考虑一下对我的孩子们的影响
think about what it's gonna do to my kids.
一天 我就给你一天
One day. I'll give you one day.
然后我就把你放在证人席上
And then I'm putting you on the stand.
路易斯 怎么了？
Louis, what's going on?
你什么意思？
What do you mean?
我刚在桌子上发现一束粉红色的康乃馨
I just found a bouquet of pink carnations on my desk.
我们都知道这是公认的道歉花束
And since we both know that's the widely accepted bouquet
我想问你为什么道歉
I thought I'd ask what you're apologizing for.
我没有向你道歉 我向希拉道歉
I wasn't apologizing to you. I was apologizing to Sheila.
结果她不想要道歉
It turns out, she didn't want an apology.
她想要回心转意
She wanted a change of heart.
而你刚刚成为高级合伙人
And you just made senior partner,
所以我想以其扔掉它们...
so I thought rather than throw them away...
谢谢你 路易斯
Thank you, Louis.
但我以为你和希拉相处得很好
But I thought you and Sheila were doing great.
是的 直到她被邀请成为
Yeah, we were until she got offered to be the dean
哥大法学院院长
of Columbia Law School.
你害怕如果她接受
And you're afraid if she takes it,
她没有时间照顾宝宝
she won't have time for the baby.
是啊 加上这一责任 卡特丽娜
Exactly, and with this added responsibility, Katrina,
我...
I...
我不知道这怎么可行
I don't know how it's gonna work.
我知道这不关我事
I know it's not my place.
但是你考虑过如果希拉时间不够
But did you consider that if Sheila has less time,
你可以争取更多的时间吗？
you might be able to make more time?
卡特里娜 我不能离开律所
Katrina, I can't just leave the firm.
我知道 路易斯 但三天前
I know that, Louis, but three nights ago,
你来我办公室 说你在我脸上
you came into my office and said you saw a look
看到了曾经在你脸上看到过的表情
on my face that you had seen on yours before.
是啊 希望有人能与你共度一生的表情
Yes, the look of wishing for someone to share your life with.
你再也没有那种表情了
You don't have that look anymore.
你拥有的是两个冠名合作人
What you do have is two name partners
还有一位新的高级合伙人在支持你
and a new senior partner who have your back.
这意味着到时候
Which means that when the time comes,
你能够退一步
you'll be able to step back a little
并相信律所掌握在好人手里
and trust that the firm is in good hands.
说到让律所掌握在好人手里
Speaking of keeping the firm in good hands,
卡特里娜 我需要告诉你一些事
Katrina, I need to tell you something.
加文 你来这里做什么？
Gavin, what are you doing here?
一小时内我们要上庭了
We're due in court in an hour.
不 我们不去 因为萨曼莎要求休庭
No we're not, because Samantha asked for a recess
她如愿以偿
and she got it.
她现在有什么把柄？
What does she have now?
不管她有什么重要的是我有什么
Doesn't matter what she has. It matters what I have.
- 那是什么？ - 一张萨曼莎·惠勒作为律师
What is that? - A list of ethical violations
为我工作六年间的道德违规清单
Samantha Wheeler engaged in over the course of six years as my attorney.
不 我不想毁了萨曼莎的职业生涯
- No, I'm not ruining Samantha's career.
你什么也不需要毁
- Look, you don't have to ruin anything.
你威胁上报律师协会 她会屈服的
You threaten to take this to the bar and she'll cave.
我不会利用这个机会的
I'm not gonna take that chance.
我们不需要 我们赢了
And we don't need to. We're winning.
不 阿历克斯 我们没有赢
No, Alex, we're not.
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?
萨曼莎今天早上来我家
Samantha came to my house this morning.
她有证据证明我问评估师
She has proof that I asked an appraiser
我的《维梅尔》价值会如何变化
what would happen to the value of my Vermeer
如果那幅画毁了
if that painting got destroyed.
- 如果他上庭 - 让我搞清楚
Now, if he gets on the stand-- - Let me get this straight.
有确凿的证据你不告诉我？
There's a goddamn smoking gun, and you kept it from me?
因为你太天真 你会把它给她的
'Cause you're a Boy Scout, and you would've given it to her.
好吧 这样
All right, look.
这很糟 但不是证据
It's bad, but it's not proof.
- 我们可以质疑这家伙 - 让我说清楚！
We can cross examine this guy and-- - Let me make myself clear!
这不是建议 这是命令
This is not a suggestion. It is an order.
如果你不做 我做
If you don't use this, I will.
如果我这样做 亚历克斯
And if I do it, Alex,
她别想安全脱身
we're gonna skip the part where she gets the chance to walk away
因为我会直接去找律师协会
because I'll be going straight to the bar.
我不喜欢你的表情
I don't like that look on your face.
什么表情
What look?
你要告诉我一些烂事的表情
The look that says you're about to tell me some serious shit.
萨曼莎被加文抓到了把柄
Samantha's got Gavin by the balls.
但我想我找到一条出路
But I think I got a way out.
- 什么出路样？ - 我查了一下
How? - I did some digging.
德克斯哈特为保护画作的
Dexhart has 80% of the reinsurance for the packing company
包装公司投了80％的再保险
that should have protected that painting.
那意味着他们有动机去掩盖他们的过错
Which means they'd have incentive to clear them of any fault.
我认为他们在报告上做了手脚
Which I believe they did with a false report.
你认为萨曼莎隐藏了真正的报告吗？
And you think Samantha's hiding the real report?
我觉得她太聪明了
I think she's too smart
一开始就看不到真正的报告
to look at the real report in the first place.
我知道如果我们用传票要它
And I know if we ask for it with a subpoena,
永远就看不到了
it'll never see the light of day.
你到底想要我做什么 阿历克斯？
What exactly are you here to ask me, Alex?
我希望你让卡特里娜·班纳特
I want you to get Katrina Bennett to go over there
去要原始的报告
and ask for the unredacted version of that report.
- 没门 - 哈维
No way. - Harvey.
你要我们的一个律师去犯罪
You're asking to have one of our lawyers commit a crime.
这不是犯罪
It's not a crime.
她是律所的高级合伙人
She's a senior partner at this firm.
她要做的就是去
All she has to do is say that,
要那份文件 然后回来
ask for the files, and get the hell out. -
如果没问题 为什么你自己不去做？
And if it's so innocent, why don't you go over there and do it yourself?
因为我不是金发女郎
Because I'm not blonde
没人会把我误认为是萨曼莎·惠勒
and no one's gonna mistake me for Samantha Wheeler.
该死的 阿历克斯 你说你可以打败她
Damn it, Alex, you said you could beat her.
我可以打败她 这就是要采取的措施
I can beat her. This is what it's gonna take.
要不是你言而无信
And I wouldn't be in this position
我今天也不会到了这个地步
if you didn't break your promise to me.
废话 因为你说
And that's bullshit because you said
你很高兴为了冠名而奋斗
you were good with fighting to get your name up.
那我该说什么？
What the hell was I supposed to say?
阿历克斯 帮助加快审判是一回事
Alex, helping to speed up the trial is one thing.
让卡特里娜去冒险
Putting Katrina at risk?
我不会这么做
I'm not doing it.
那你要知道 我不这样做
Then you should know, I don't do this,
加文·安德鲁斯明天会去律师协会
Gavin Andrews goes to the bar tomorrow
告发多年来萨曼莎所做的不光彩的事
with a list of shady things Samantha's done over the years.
所以随你帮不帮我
So you can help me with this or not.
她的名字都不会出现在那堵墙上了
Either way, her name's not going on that wall.
卡特里娜 如果你想今晚出去喝一杯
Katrina, if you're here to go out for drinks tonight,
我只能说答案很明显
I can only say that the answer is a big, fat,
“是的 请”
"Yes, please."
尽管我很乐意说我也想这样
As much as I would love to say that's why I'm here,
但我需要的是一条很明显的建议
what I need is a big, fat piece of advice.
- 什么事？ - 哈维
What is it? - Harvey...
基本上就是让我去冒充萨曼莎·惠勒
basically asked me to impersonate Samantha Wheeler.
什么？
What?
只有这个办法帮阿历克斯获胜
It's the only way to get what they need to help Alex win.
你怎么告诉他的？
What'd you tell him?
我告诉他我不知道
I told him I didn't know.
好吧 如果哈维想要你这样做
Well, if Harvey wants you to do this,
为什么不做呢？
why not do it?
除了不想害萨曼莎不说
Other than not wanting to get on Samantha's bad side,
路易斯特意告诉
Louis specifically told me
他俩谁也不要帮
not to help either one of them.
他说原因了吗？
Did he say why?
他说如果有太多人介入
He said that if too many people got involved,
争斗可能会让律所分崩离析
their fight could tear the firm apart.
那我要说......
Then I say...
太多人已经参与其中了
too many people are already involved.
你也可以管它呢 帮助哈维
You might as well go ahead. Help Harvey.
谢谢 唐娜
Thanks, Donna.
这是什么？
What's this?
和解协议
A settlement agreement.
放弃诉讼 支付加文的律师费
You're dropping that lawsuit, paying Gavin's legal fees,
并发表公开道歉
and issuing a public apology.
见鬼了
The hell we are.
萨曼莎 随你怎么叫
Samantha, you can kick and scream all you want,
但是我有包装公司克扣材料的证据
but I got proof the packing company skimped on materials
而且你的客户知道这件事
and your client knew about it.
你是怎么得到这些的？
How the ---- did you get these?
就像平常我做的一样
The same way I got everything else.
你跟我分享了发现
You shared it with me in discovery.
我才没跟你分享
I didn't share shit with you.
我甚至都没见过这些文件
I never even saw these documents.
你没见过 因为你从未想看它
You never saw them because you never wanted to see them.
但是德克斯哈特保险公司
But Dexhart Insurance has
有记录证明文件送来过
records proving it was sent.
你这个混蛋 你作弊
You son of a bitch. You cheated.
不 我只是按你的规则行事
No, I just played by your rules.
所以不要哭
So don't start crying now.
哦 我才不哭呢
Oh, I'm not crying.
我肯定不会签这个
And I as sure as hell am not signing this.
让我告诉你如果不这样做会发生什么
And let me tell you what happens if you don't.
加文·安德鲁斯会让你被吊销律师资格
Gavin Andrews gets you disbarred.
- 什么？ - 他有些东西
What? - He's got information
可能会结束你的职业生涯
that could end your career
他要我利用它 但我没有
and he told me to use it, but I didn't
因为我不想那样对你
because I didn't wanna do that to you.
那又如何
So, what?
我应该感谢你吗？
I'm supposed to thank you now?
我不指望你感谢我
I don't expect you to thank me,
但我确实希望你接受已经结束了
but I do expect you to accept that it's over.
我不接受任何事情
I'm not accepting anything.
我知道了
I get it.
你不习惯失败
You're not used to losing.
但无论你是否愿意承认
But whether you wanna admit it or not,
我赢了 你输了
I won, you lost.
明天我的名字就会挂在那堵墙上了
And come tomorrow, my name's going up on that wall.
路易斯 你来做什么？
Louis, what are you doing here?
不是给你带更多的花来
Not bringing you more flowers,
如果那是你以为的话
if that's what you're wondering.
希拉 我那么害怕你承担
Sheila, the reason I was so thrown with you taking on
更多责任的原因是......
more responsibility was because...
我害怕我要承担更多的责任
I was afraid that I wouldn't be able to take on less.
无论你是否得到这个终身职位
And whether you are offered the permanent position or not,
在时机成熟时
when the time comes,
我想为我们的家人花更多时间
I wanna take time for our family.
好吧 我很高兴听到你这么说
Well, I'm--I'm glad to hear you say that.
因为时机已成熟
Because the time has come.
你是说你得到那个终身职位了？
You mean you were offered the permanent position?
不 不是那个 路易斯
No, not that time, Louis.
另一个
The other time.
哦 我的天
Oh, my God.
你说的是我认为你在说的吗？
Are you saying what I think you're saying?
今天下午我见了查斯
I saw Chaz this afternoon.
手术不需要做了 因为...
And we're not gonna need that surgery because...
我们要有个孩子了
we're gonna have a baby.
难以置信 你确定吗？
I don't believe this. Are you sure?
我的意思是......
I mean...
你绝对确定吗？
are you absolutely sure?
是的 我很肯定
Yes, I'm positive.
我很抱歉我们吵架了
And I'm sorry we fought.
我只是太紧张了
I just--I'm stressed,
全身都是荷尔蒙
and I've got hormones running through me
我甚至不确定我是否想要这个终身职位
and I'm not even sure if I want that permanent position.
嘿 没关系
Hey, it's okay.
一切都会好起来的
It's all gonna be okay.
我就在你身边 哪也不会去
I am right here by your side. I'm not going anywhere.
你怎么这么冷静？
How are you so calm?
因为我知道现在什么对我最重要
Because I know what's important to me now.
就是这事
And it's this.
一切都会好的
Everything's gonna be okay.
好吧
Okay.
我收到了你的消息 你迟到了
I got your message. You're late.
我有一些想法
I had some thinking to do.
好吧 我很高兴你现身了
Well, I'm glad you showed up.
因为我开始怀疑今晚是见到你
Because I was beginning to wonder if I was meeting you
还是联邦调查局
or the feds in here tonight.
我想我有办法让你摆脱这种局面
I think I have a way to get you out of this.
介意我问你为什么改变主意吗？
You mind if I ask you what changed your mind?
因为我相信你
Because I believe you.
我也知道如果我这样做
I also know if I do this for you,
你会永远支持我的
you'll always have my back.
你是说我欠你的？
You're saying I owe you?
我说你会感激不尽
I'm saying you'll feel grateful.
这不是一回事
It isn't the same thing.
是啊 那不是
No, it's not.
那么你的计划是什么？
So, what's your plan?
在这里你更信任谁？
Who here do you trust more than anyone else?
今晚过后 这很容易 你
After tonight, that's easy. You.
不 不能是我
No, it can't be me.
太引人注目了
It raises too many red flags.
此外我还不够老 还轮不到我
Besides, I'm not old enough. It's not my time.
嗯 你在说什么？
Well, what are you talking about?
回答问题
Just answer the question.
你需要有人来支持你
You need somebody here to have your back.
那不是我 还有谁？
It isn't me. Who is it?
两个人
Two people.
艾伦·兰德和埃里克·卡尔多
Ellen Rand and Eric Kaldor.
那就争取他们
Then get them.
因为我们还没有走出困境
'Cause we're not out of the woods yet.
你和我联系是件好事
It's good that you reached out to me when you did.
我还在想你做了错误的选择
I was starting to think you made a wrong choice.
汤姆 我已经做了太多的错误选择
I've made enough wrong choices in my life, Tom.
我不会在这个问题上再犯错
I'm not gonna make a wrong one on this.
- 那么你发现了什么？ - 一无所有
So, what'd you find? - Nothing.
我发现的只是计费系统中的一个小故障
All I found was a glitch in the billing system.
胡说 我们有消息说
Bullshit, we've got information that your firm--
我不在乎你有什么
I don't care what you've got.
客户被多收钱又退回去了
Clients were overcharged then reimbursed.
就是这回事
That's all there was to it.
当我传唤过去五年的每个账单记录时
And when I subpoena every billing record from the last five years,
那绝对会有问题
that's never gonna hold up.
如果你可以传唤那些记录
And if you could have subpoenaed those records,
你不会在第一时间来找我
you wouldn't have come to me in the first place.
我知道了
I get it.
他们买通你了
They paid you off,
现在你和他们一样有罪
and now you're as guilty as they are, huh?
别那样说我说
Don't you say that to me.
你试图用我的过去让我背叛我的家庭
You tried to used my history to get me to turn on my family.
如果你启封我的记录 我向你保证
And if you unseal my records, I guarantee you
兰德-卡尔多-赞恩律师事务所
the firm of Rand Kaldor Zane
会利用一切资源
will use every resource they have to come after you
起诉你诬告
for malicious prosecution.
兰德-卡尔多-赞恩律师事务所？
Rand Kaldor Zane?
贾维斯 埃利斯和格林都辞职了
That's right. Jarvis, Ellis, and Green are all stepping down,
所以如果你确信他们真的做了什么
so if you're convinced they really did something,
把它当作被传唤的一点惩罚
think of it as a little punishment getting served after all.
那不是惩罚
That's not punishment.
这是逍遥法外
That's getting away scot-free.
如果你认为一生努力工作
And if you think having your name ripped off the wall
得到的冠名被剥夺不是一种惩罚
when you've worked your entire life to get up there isn't punishment,
你完全不知道一名律师追求的是什么
you don't know what it is to be a lawyer.
相信我这是我们所有人梦寐以求的
Because trust me, it's all any of us ever want.
那你为什么不把自己的名字放上去？
Then why didn't you put your own name up there?
因为这还轮不到我 汤姆
Because it's not my time, Tom.
但有一天会的
But you can bet your ass someday it will be.
萨曼莎
Samantha.
你来告诉我你赢了吗？
Are you here to tell me you won?
我来告诉你阿历克斯·威廉姆斯有确凿的证据
I'm here to tell you Alex Williams has a smoking gun.
他让我输得很惨
And he's got me dead to rights.
什么
What?
我输了 罗伯特
I lost, Robert.
结束了
It's over.
这到底是怎么回事
How the hell did that happen?
我吃定他了
I had him.
我踩着加文的脖子
I had my foot on Gavin's neck.
但我给了他喘息的机会
I gave him extra time.
但我不会失去我应得的
And I'm not gonna lose what's mine
因为亚历克斯利用那个机会赢了
because Alex used that time to win.
你在说什么
What are you saying?
我不同意协议的内容
I don't give a shit what the agreement was.
我的名字得挂在墙上
My name's going up on that wall,
而您要实现它
and you're gonna make it happen.
- 我做不到 - 为什么
I can't do that. - Why not?
- 萨曼莎 - 该死的 罗伯特！
Samantha-- - God damn it, Robert!
他们找到了那些文件
They found those files,
这意味着你没有起决定性作用
which means you didn't tip the scales at all.
你有什么需要选边站的？
What is it gonna take for you to get off the sidelines?
如果你没有加文·安德鲁斯手软
I wouldn't have to get off the sidelines
我就不必选边站了
if you hadn't shown Gavin Andrews mercy!
好吧 我手软因为他还是客户
Well, I didn't just do that because he's still a client.
我这样做是因为他告诉我他有家庭
I did it because he told me he had a family.
就像你曾经做过的那样
Just like you once did.
你说我欠你的
You're saying I owe you.
你欠我很多年了 你知道的
You have owed me for years, and you know it.
在你对他们保证之前
And before you gave them your word,
你先对我保证的
you gave your word to me.
所以问题是
So the question is,
你要辜负哪个保证
which word are you gonna live up to?
路易斯 我们需要谈谈 这很重要
Louis, we need to talk. It's important.
嗯 当然咯 进来吧
Yeah, of course. Come in.
很高兴你还在
Actually, I'm glad you're here,
因为我有一些重大的私事
'cause I have some big news of my own.
好吧 不管什么事 都没有这事大
Well, whatever it is, it's not as big as this.
罗伯特要告诉哈维他会
Robert's about to tell Harvey that he's gonna put up
让萨曼莎冠名而不是阿历克斯
Samantha's name instead of Alex's.
不 不 阿历克斯赢了
No, no, Alex won.
罗伯特不能像那样说话不算数
Robert can't break his word like that.
嗯 他会的 如果我们什么都不做
Well, he's going to, and if we don't do something,
明天律所就不存在了
we're not gonna have a firm tomorrow.
我们会有一场大战
We're gonna have a war on our hands.
好的 我明白了
Okay, I hear you.
明天一早我们开会
First thing tomorrow we'll get into a conference room
把这事谈清楚
and we'll talk this thing through.
路易斯 为时已晚
Louis, it's too late for that.
谈已经没用了
The time for talking is over.
我们需要做点什么
We need to do something.
要做的是
And that something is--
我退下来
I'll step down.
什么
What?
唐娜 希拉怀孕了
Donna, Sheila's pregnant.
我要做父亲了
I'm gonna be a father.
哦 太好了
Oh, my God.
无论如何我都会退下来
I was gonna ratchet down anyway.
这样他们俩都可以冠名
This way they can both put their names up.
路易斯 我为你感到非常高兴
Louis, I am so happy for you.
但这没用的
But that's not gonna work.
你什么意思
What are you saying?
我意思是你需站出来做管理合伙人
I'm saying you need to step in as managing partner.
- 什么？ - 路易斯
What? - Louis,
罗伯特现在无法管理律所
Robert can't run this firm right now
哈维也不能 你是唯一能够做到的人
and neither can Harvey. You're the only one who can.
对不起 唐娜我不能
Sorry, Donna. I can't.
为什么不能
Why not?
因为我不是一个领袖
Because I'm not a leader.
他们不会听我的
They won't follow me.
路易斯
Louis.
我知道你找卡特里娜保护律所
I know you went to Katrina to protect the firm.
你刚刚想退下来也是在做同样的事
And you just offered to step down to do the same thing.
如果那不是我们现在需要的领袖
If that's not the leadership we need right now,
我不知道是什么
I don't know what is.
为什么要是现在
Why does it have to be now?
我只想做一个父亲
I just wanna be a father.
我最不想做的事就是
And the last thing I'd ever wanna do
让你做不成父亲
is take that away from you.
但宝宝的预产期还有九个月
But your baby's not due for another nine months.
律所也是你的宝贝
And this firm is your baby too,
它现在就需要你
and it needs you right now.
不先跟希拉谈过 我无法决定
I can't make that decision without talking to Sheila first.
那就快点
Then hurry.
我们没有很多时间了
Because we don't have a lot of time.
唐娜 即使我同意......
Donna, even if I said yes...
哈维和罗伯特永远不会同意
Harvey and Robert would never vote
让我成为管理合伙人
to make me managing partner.
让我想办法
You leave that to me.
我想你在庆祝
I take it you're celebrating.
一杯酒而已 罗伯特
It's a drink, Robert.
我不想让人难堪
I'm not rubbing it in anybody's face,
但是我为自己的人感到高兴
but yeah, I'm happy for my guy.
好吧 我要说的事
Well, I'm here to say something
会让你不那么开心的
that's gonna make you less happy.
什么事
What's that?
我要让萨曼莎冠名 而不是亚历克斯
I'm putting Samantha's name on the wall, not Alex's.
我是不是老了 因为......
I must be getting old because...
我很确定我刚刚听到你说
I'm pretty sure I just heard you say
你在违背你的承诺
you're breaking your word.
哈维 我知道我做了一个承诺
Harvey, I know. I made a promise.
你不只是做出承诺
You didn't just make a promise.
你看着我的眼睛说
You looked me in the eye and you said,
“让我们在赛场上解决这个问题”
"Let's settle this in the ring."
我不在乎 我欠她的
And I don't care. I owe her.
那几年前就应该让她冠名你自己的律所了
Then you should have put her name up years ago.
而不是让别人花代价
Not when it costs someone else.
见鬼 我是律所的管理合伙人
God damn it, I am the managing partner of this firm.
我们现在就可以改
And we can change that right now
因为你没来以前我就在这里了
because I was here before you
你离开之后我还会一直在这里
and I'm gonna be here long after you're gone.
你在威胁我吗
Are you threatening me?
我在给你一个选择
I'm giving you a choice.
你和萨曼莎可以接受阿历克斯
You and Samantha can accept Alex
或者打包走人
or you can pack up your shit right now.
我哪里也不去 萨曼莎也是
I'm not going anywhere and neither is Samantha,
因为你代表过去 她代表未来
because you're the past, and she's the future.
在这里不是
Not here, she's not.
现在离开我办公室
Now get the ---- out of my office.
够了
That's enough.
谁也别走
No one's going anywhere,
你俩谁也不是管理合伙人
and neither one of you is managing partner anymore.
唐娜 别管闲事
- Donna, stay out of this.
不 我要阻止这事
No, I am putting a stop to this,
现在就阻止
and I'm putting a stop to it right now.
因为这不仅仅是一次友好的聚会
'Cause this isn't just a friendly gathering.
这是一次正式的合伙人会议
This is a formal partner meeting.
接下来
And here's how it's gonna go.
我提名路易斯担任管理合伙人
I'm voting for Louis for managing partner.
他会投票给自己
And he's voting for himself.
既然你们俩不可能投票给对方
And since there is no way that either one of you is voting for the other,
不如你们也投票给他
you might as well both vote for him
保持这个统一战线
and keep this a united front.
因为别搞错 路易斯是管理合伙人
Because make no mistake. Louis is managing partner.
废话
Bullshit.
你无法实现它
There's no way you're pulling this off.
罗伯特 她无法 我可以
She's not pulling this off, Robert. I am.
无论你喜不喜欢都会发生
This is happening whether you like it or not.
你认为你有管理律所的能力吗
So you think you have what it takes to run this firm?
我知道我有
I know I do.
我要做的第一件事
And my first order of business
就是同时晋升阿历克斯和萨曼莎
is promoting Alex and Samantha at the same time.
任何称职的管理合伙人
And any managing partner worth his salt
都明白他们永远不会接受
can see they'll never go for it.
没错 但他们要么接受
No. They're either both gonna accept this
要要么走人
or they're both gonna walk the ---- out the door
因为我受够了
because I am sick of this shit.
让我告诉你们
And I'll tell you something else.
你们俩最好说服他们
You two are gonna goddamn sell it to them.
不然呢
So, what's it gonna be?
我 路易斯和一个不一致的决定？
Me and Louis and a split decision?
或者我们让这件事一致
Or are we gonna make this thing unanimous?
他们怎么接受的？
How'd they take it?
又哭又闹
Kicking and screaming.
打赌你没有退让
Bet you wouldn't have it any other way.
没有 我不会
Nope, I wouldn't. -
你告诉兰德和卡尔多什么？
What'd you tell Rand and Kaldor?
他们所要做的就是准备好负责
That all they had to do was be ready to act in charge,
我可以让他们得到律所
and I could get them the firm.
让我猜一下
And let me guess.
他们知道再也别问这个问题了
They knew not to ask any more questions than that.
这不是做一个大律师的全部意义吗？
Isn't that what being a great lawyer is all about?
有时候
Sometimes.
有时是提出正确的问题
Sometimes it's about asking the right questions.
好吧
Okay, then.
你为什么这么做
Why'd you do it?
做什么
Do what?
帮我
Help me.
别跟我说是要我一直挺你
And don't give me that line about always having your back,
因为一定还有其他更多的东西
because it's gotta be about something more.
我没有父亲
I didn't have a father.
什么
What?
我不知道我的父母是谁
I have no idea who my parents were.
甚至不知道他们的名字
Didn't even know their names.
我辗转在寄养家庭里
I bounced around the foster care system.
从未在同一个地方生活超过两年
Never lived in the same place for more than two years.
跟这有什么关系
What does that have to do with--
你的女儿
Your daughter.
我帮你 因为我会付出一切
I helped you because I would have given anything
给像你这样照应我的人
to have someone like you looking out for me.
而且我不想让她失去
And I didn't wanna take it away from her.
我不知道该说些什么
I don't know what to say.
说从现在起永远有人
Say that from now on I'll always have someone
会挺我
looking out for me.
罗伯特
Robert.
萨曼莎 坐下
Samantha, have a seat.
我不想坐
I don't want one.
除非你说的是一个席位
Unless you're saying it's a seat at the table.
是的
It is.
但不只有你
But you're not alone.
阿历克斯也升职
Alex is getting a promotion too.
开玩笑吗
Are you kidding me?
只冠名一个的重点
The whole point of there being only one
是让它变得有意义
is to have it mean something.
我知道重点是什么 萨曼莎
I know what the point is, Samantha.
所以你出卖了我
So you sold me out.
我谁也没有出卖
I didn't sell anyone out!
我曾经告诉过你我会照顾你
I once told you I'd look out for you.
我脑子里一直这么想
And I let that get in my head
几乎让我们失去这里的一切
and it almost cost us what we have here.
所以现在我要用
So now I'm gonna look out for you in a way
一开始就应该用的方式来照顾你
that I should have in the first place.
什么方式
How's that?
告诉你实话
By telling you the truth.
他们在我们自己的比赛中赢了 萨曼莎
They beat us at our own game, Samantha.
不管我们是否喜欢
Whether we like it or not.
但你知道这意味着什么吗？
But you know what that means?
我们周围都是坏蛋
We are surrounded by some badass people.
所以让我们休战
So let's stop fighting in here
一致对外
and start fighting everyone else out there.
因为是时候和平了
Because it's time to make peace.
我打扰了吗
Am I interrupting?
因为我想说哈维告诉我这个消息
Because I wanted to say Harvey gave me the news,
如果你没意见 我也接受
and I'm good with it if you are.
我当然接受 合伙人
Of course I am, partner.
我想只有一件事要搞清楚
Then I guess there's only one thing to figure out.
是威廉姆斯-惠勒还是惠勒-威廉姆斯
Williams-Wheeler or Wheeler-Williams.
你赢了 亚历克斯 你选择
You won, Alex. It's your choice.
让我们来一个
So what do you say we have ourselves
老式团体拥抱怎么样
a good old-fashioned group hug?
* 今晚在空中我能感觉到它 *
* I can feel it coming in the air tonight *
* 哦 主啊
* Oh, Lord
* 我一直在等待这一刻 *
* And I've been waiting for this moment for all my life *
* 哦 主啊
* Oh, Lord
哈维 漫长的一天
Harvey, it's been a long day,
如果你是来训我的
so if you're here to yell at me--
放松 路易斯 我来说声谢谢
Relax, Louis. I'm here to say thank you.
我们迷失了自己 你把我们带回来了
We lost ourselves and you brought us back.
谢谢 哈维 感谢
Thanks, Harvey. Appreciate that.
那样对我和罗伯特需要很大的勇气
It takes a lot of balls to come at me and Robert like that.
不 哈维 不需要
No, Harvey, it didn't.
因为第一次
Because for the first time,
我不在乎你们如何看我 因为......
I didn't care how either one of you saw me because...
一开始我甚至都不想成为管理合伙人
I didn't even care to be managing partner in the first place.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
我要有孩子了 哈维
I'm gonna have a baby, Harvey.
我会成为一个爸爸了
I'm gonna be a dad.
知道那个消息
And once that hit me,
处理这个感觉就简单多了
dealing with this felt so simple.
祝贺你 路易斯
Congratulations, Louis.
我想你会成为很棒的管理合伙人的
I think you're gonna make a great managing partner,
而且我知道你会成为一个杰出的父亲
and I know you're gonna make an outstanding father.
你们两个需要开一个房间吗
You two need to get a room?
还是想出去庆祝一下
Or does anybody wanna go out and celebrate?
我想留在这里
Actually I think I'm just gonna stay here for a bit
整理一下思路
and take it all in.
我明白
I understand.
晚安 路易斯
Good night, Louis.
晚安
Good night.
跟我说实话
Level with me.
你真的认为他能行吗
You really think he can handle this?
我认为绝望的时候需要孤注一掷
I think desperate times require desperate measures.
我还想到其他东西
And I think something else too.
什么
What's that?
我会高兴看到
I'm going to enjoy watching
你和罗伯特接受路易斯的命令
you and Robert take orders from Louis.
我们不会是他唯一管的人
We're not gonna be the only ones he's in charge of.
他也会给你很多命令的
He'll be giving you plenty of orders, too.
不 他不会的 你忘记了
No, he won't. You're forgetting.
我是路易斯的耳边风
I'm the Louis Whisperer.
你确定吗
Are you sure about that?
当时他说你搞不定这事 他能
When he walked in, he said you weren't pulling it off. He was.
你以为是谁要他这么说的
And who do you think told him to say that?
天哪 你是说你才是真正的管理合伙人？
Holy shit, are you saying you're the real managing partner?
我没有这么说
I'm not saying that.
但我也没有不这么说
But I'm also not not saying that.
来吧 帅哥 喝酒你请客
Come on, pretty. Drinks are on you.
* 当日子变得艰难
* When times get hard
* 那是我开始出发的时候
* That's when I get going
* 因为我无法停止 我不会停止 *
* 'Cause I can't stop, I won't stop *
* 一旦我起步 那么就没有什么能阻止我 *
* And once I get rolling, then there ain't no holding me *
* 我无法停止 我不会停止 *
* I can't stop, I won't stop *